Push it to pop it! Rock it to lock it! Break it to make it!
Breakin' is a music, drama, romance film directed by Joel Silberg.
A struggling young dancer joins forces with two breakdancers
and together they become a street sensation.
Kelly / Special K, played by Lucinda Dickey.
Ozone, played by Adolfo Quinones.
Turbo, played by Michael Chambers.
Franco, played by Ben Lokey.
James, played by Christopher McDonald.
Adam, played by Phineas Newborn III.
Breakin' (also known as Breakdance in the United Kingdom and Break Street '84 in other regions) is a 1984 American breakdancing-themed musical film directed by
Joel Silberg and written by Charles Parker and Allen DeBevoise based on a story by Parker, DeBevoise and Gerald Scaife about dancer Alysha Williams.
The film's setting was inspired by a 1983 documentary titled Breakin' 'n' Enterin', set in the
multi-racial hip hop club Radio-Tron, based out of MacArthur Park in Los Angeles.
Many of the artists and dancers from that documentary, including Ice-T (who makes his film debut as a club MC), and
Michael "Boogaloo Shrimp" Chambers, went straight from Breakin' 'n' Enterin' to star in Breakin'.
The film's soundtrack featured the hits "Breakin'...
There's No Stopping Us" by Ollie & Jerry, "Freakshow on the Dance Floor" by
The Bar-Kays and the UK Top 20 hit "Body Work" by Hot Streak.
Breakin' was one of the final Cannon film productions released by MGM/UA.
After release, MGM and Cannon dissolved their distribution deal, reportedly over the potentially X-rated content in John Derek's film Bolero and
MGM's then-policy of not theatrically releasing X-rated material, forcing Cannon to become an in-house distribution company once again.
Because of this, Breakin' is considered to be the final
financially profitable film released by Cannon.
Breakin' was released to theaters on May 4, 1984, and despite receiving
negative reviews from critics, it was a box office success.
A theatrical sequel entitled Breakin' 2: Electric
Boogaloo was released later in the same year.
The film explores themes of dancing, rap music,
hip-hop, street gang, breakdance.
The tone is emotional.